Guide to the School of Architecture, Yale University, Reminiscences and Memorabilia of Students in the Classes 1948-1958
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Architecture, Yale University, reminiscences and memorabilia of students in the Classes 1948-1958
1948-2004
RU 961
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4
(4 boxes)
The material, assembled by Estelle Margolis and Walfredo Toscanini, consists of reminiscences, student and later work, course materials, and articles by former Yale architecture students who graduated from 1948 to 1958.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 18-H (YRG 18-H), Audio-visual materials and memorabilia documenting the School of Art and Architecture.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The material was a gift of Estelle Margolis and Walfredo Toscanini, 2004 and 2005.
Scope and Contents
The material, assembled by Estelle Margolis and Walfredo Toscanini, consists of reminiscences, student and later work, course materials, and articles by former Yale architecture students who graduated from 1948 to 1958.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by year of graduation or type of material.
Architecture -- Study and teaching; Schools of architecture; Architects; Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. School of Architecture and Design; Yale University. School of Fine Arts
- Series I
  - Class lists and index (Box 1)
  - Class of 1948
    - Miller, Henry F. (Box 1)
    - Nalle, Eugene (Box 1)
  - Class of 1949
    - Bogen, Herber (Box 1)
    - Chapman, Frank R., Jr. (Box 1)
    - Critz, Richard I. (Box 1)
    - Fernandez, Elvira (Box 1)
    - Hamilton, Abigail McCormick (Box 1)
    - Sovik, Edward A (Box 1)
  - Class of 1950
    - Carter, John A. (Box 1)
    - Headstrom, Richard W. (Box 1)
    - Kuhn, Jean H. (Box 1)
    - Nelson, Edward H. (Box 1)
    - O"Brien, John (Box 1)
    - Switzer, WIlliam (Box 1)
    - Verpillot, Paul R. (Box 1)
    - West, J. (Box 1)
  - Class of 1951
    - Bultman, Phelps H. (Box 1)
    - Carlin, Earl P. (Box 1)
    - Comey, Ralph H. (Box 1)
    - DeYoung, Ross (Box 1)
    - Firestone, Nathaniel (Box 1)
    - Metcalf, William H., Jr. (Box 1)
    - Millard, Peter (Box 1)
  - Class of 1952
    - Boyer, Frank (Box 1)
    - Cannon, Winthrop P. (Box 1)
    - Gobbs, Dale (Box 1)
    - Huff, William (Box 1)
    - Noyes, Herbert M. (Box 1)
    - Wollen, Evans (Box 1)
  - Class of 1953
    - Bass, Robinson Neil (Box 1)
    - Bishop, Minor L. (Box 1)
    - Buell, Duncan W. (Box 1)
    - Greimann, Stanley V. (Box 1)
    - Harrover, Roy (Box 1)
    - Harter, R Edward (Box 1)
    - Kulski, Julian (Box 1)
    - Mahaffey, Fred (Box 1)
    - Perry, Donald (Box 1)
    - Shiffer, Edward (Box 1)
  - Class of 1954
    - Bascom, Mansfield (Box 1)
    - Bowles, Chester, Jr. (Box 1)
    - Brickbauer, Charles G. (Box 1)
    - Brown, Horace H. (Box 1)
    - Brunjes, George Richard (Box 1)
    - Carver, Joan Wilson (Box 1)
    - Carver, Norman F., Jr. (Box 1)
    - Gibans, James D. (Box 1)
    - Ilmanen, J. William (Box 1)
    - Lee, John Francis, Jr. (Box 1)
    - Vreeland, Thomas R., Jr. (Box 1)
  - Class of 1955
    - Emery, Vica Schniewind (Box 1)
    - Faulkner, Avery (Box 1)
    - Field, John L. (Box 1)
    - Graves, Thomas Freeman (Box 1)
    - Henderson, Arthur Smythe (Box 1)
    - Jacobsen, Hugh Newell (Box 1)
    - Kaplan, Walter (Box 1)
    - Margolis, Estelle Thompson (Box 1)
    - Polshek, James Stewart (Box 1)
    - Rullman, Edward F. (Box 1)
    - Sisk, Sidney (Box 1)
    - Tetrault, Patricia Vestutti (Box 1)
    - Toscanni, Walfredo (Box 1)
  - Class of 1956
    - Chase, Alan L. (Box 1)
    - Grindereng, William (Box 1)
    - Henniger, Gerald E. (Box 1)
    - McNair, James D. (Box 1)
    - Nalle, Leona Annenberg (Box 1)
    - Ramberg, Walter D. (Box 1)
    - Wright, Stanley B. (Box 1)
  - Class of 1957
    - Ames, Ernest (Box 1)
    - Glenney, Edmund J., II (Box 1)
    - Handley, James H., Jr. (Box 1)
    - Mogel, Lee (Box 1)
    - Nininger, Richard (Box 1)
  - Class of 1958
    - Beckman, Ronald (Box 1)
    - Hardenbergh, Mark H. (Box 1)
    - Heimsath, Clovis (Box 1)
    - Houk, John F. (Box 1)
    - Kagan, Nathan (Box 1)
    - Pasanella, Giovanni (Box 1)
    - Perry, Charles O. (Box 1)
    - Stuhldreher, Michael W. (Box 1)
    - Van Dine, Harold F. (Box 1)
  - Books, magazines, art work (Box 2)
    - West, J. (class of 1950) (Box 2)
    - Gibbs, Dale (class of 1952) (Box 2)
    - Bishop, Minor L. (class of 1953) (Box 2)
    - Kulski, Julian (class of 1953) (Box 2)
    - Margolis, Estelle (class of 1955) (Box 2)
  - Oversize
    - Drawings prepared for distribution in courses (Box 3)
    - Gibbs, Dale (class of 1952), College Activities Building (Box 4)
- Memorabilia of Architecture Students in the School of Fine Arts and the School of Architecture and Design, circa 1948-1956; Accession 2005-A-140
  - Class of 1948 (Box 1)
    - Nalle, Eugene (Box 1)
  - Class of 1949
    - Bogen, Herbert (Box 1)
    - Critz, Richard I. (Box 1)
  - Class of 1952
    - Cannon, Winthrop P. (Box 1)
    - Huff, William (Box 1)
  - Class of 1953
    - Perry, Donald (Box 1)
  - Class of 1954
    - Bascom, Mansfield (Box 1)
    - Brickbauer, Charles G. (Box 1)
    - Brunjes, George Richard (Box 1)
    - Cregeau, David Groves (Box 1)
    - Ilmanen, J. William (Box 1)
  - Class of 1955
    - Polshek, James Stewart (Box 1)
  - Class of 1956
    - Nalle, Leona Annenberg (Box 1)
    - Ramberg, William D. (Box 1)